[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So when we map data, we figure out how to convert the data
我们要映射数据时 需要知道
into some graphics primitive that we can display, and that conversion
如何将数据转换成可被展示的原始图形
is going to depend on how we perceive different graphical objects and
这个转换取决于我们对不同的图形对象的理解
connect their characteristics to the characteristics of the data.
要把图形的特点和数据的特点相联系
So, as we saw before,
所以 正如我们前面所看到的
the data visualization framework has this mapping layer.
数据可视化的结构里存在这样一个映射层
And this mapping layer takes data in our data collection, and
这个映射层从数据集合中读取数据
takes its abstract data values, and
抽象出数据的值
assigns them more concrete geometric values, and those geometric
然后赋予它们更多具体的几何意义
values are used by the graphics layer to display the data for visualization.
这些几何意义会在图形层被可视化出来
So there's been some studies in the 80s that basically uncovered
20世纪80年代 有一些研究基本揭示了
how effective different geometric mappings are in
不同的几何映射表示的方法 对于定量数值的映射
the perception of quantitative values that they're mapped to.
是如何的有效
So, for example, we have this list here, and it's sorted by perceptual accuracy.
举个例子 这里有个列表 表中的元素按人们认知中的准确度排序
So when we see data
当我们查看数据时
Indicated by mapping to position, we do a better job
相比起映射到“颜色”或“密度” 映射到“位置”
of understanding the quantities than we do if the data is mapped to color or density.
会使我们对定量的“量”有更好的理解
So, if we have data varying along the horizontal axis here,
所以 如果我们有沿着横轴变化的数据
we can map the data to position.
我们可以将数据映射到“位置”
And we can see that the right bar is farther along.
这里 我们能够看到 右侧的竖线会更长
It's higher than the left bar.
它的位置比左侧的要更高
It's got a greater position.
它的“位置”更高
And, in fact, we can see how much greater the position is.
并且 我们还能够看“位置”高出了多少
We can also see it from length, and the right bar is longer than the left bar.
我们还可以从“长度”的角度来看 右侧的竖线要比左侧的长
And these are very good methods for displaying quantitative data.
这些 都是展示定量的数据的好方法
And you can see that if you combine the two of these,
另外 你可以看到 如果把二者结合起来，
you basically get the elements of a bar chart.
你基本就有了一个条形图的所有组成
Similarly, you can map data to angle or slope,
同样的 你也可以把数据映射到“角度”或者“斜率”
and you can see that this right angle is greater than this left angle.
你会发现 右侧夹角的“角度”要比左侧的大
That's a little bit less effective, but
虽然这看起来效果不太明显 但是
these are the elements that you would see in a pie chart, and pie charts are just
这些元素是你会在饼图中看到的元素 而饼图
a little less effective at displaying quantitative data than are bar charts.
相较条形图而言 在展示定量数据方面 确实效果会稍逊一筹
You can also map data to area.
你也可以把数据映射到“面积”上
And so the circle on the right is smaller than the circle on the left.
这时 右侧的圆圈比左侧的要小
It represents a smaller area.
因为它表示着一个较小的面积
It's just a little harder to figure out how much smaller
不过要说明右侧的圆圈比左侧的小了多少
the circle on the right is than the circle on the left.
是有些困难的
And you can also map to volume, and so the sphere on the right
你还可以（把数据）映射到“体积”上 右侧的球体
represents a smaller volume than the sphere on the left, but
所表示的“体积”要比左侧球体的小一些 但是
it's even more difficult to figure out how much smaller the volume is here
这就更难以判断出
in the orange sphere on the right than it is for the blue sphere on the left.
右侧橙色球的“体积”比左侧蓝色球的小了多少
And finally, color or density.
最后 就是 颜色和密度
In this case, we have two equal size spheres.
这一次 我们有两个大小相同的球
This sphere on the right is lighter, and the sphere on the left is darker.
右侧的球颜色较浅 左侧的球颜色较深
It's just difficult to know how much lighter the sphere on the right is,
这就真的很难判断 相比起左边的
compared to the sphere on the left.
右边的球颜色浅了多少
So it's interesting to note that, as we move farther down the list and
所以 有意思的是 当我们越往列表的下方移动
find less effective ways of mapping data to geometric or spatial values,
就越难以将数据有效地映射到几何值或者空间值上
that we move from one-dimensional values of position, length,
从一维的位置 长度
angle, and slope to two-dimensional values, or
夹角 斜率到二维数值 直到
three-dimensional values, of area or volume.
三维的面积 体积等
And when we get to color or density,
当我们转向颜色和密度时
we're no longer talking about spatial values at all.
我们就已经不是在讨论空间值了
These are non-spatial values.
它们是非空间值
And so further studies have investigated this at a finer level of detail and
一些研究在更细致的层面对此进行了探索
expanded that list.
并扩充了这个列表
Again, we have position and length being the most effective
当然 位置和长度是最有效的
representations of data for spatially, or geometrically.
用于数据的空间 或几何表示
But, for example, angle and slope have been divided so
但是 举个例子 角度和斜率就被区分开了
that angle is slightly better than slope for discerning quantitative values.
于是角度在定量数值的分辨上要稍微优于斜率
And, finally, density has been expanded to density, saturation, and hue, so
最后 密度被扩展成了密度 饱和度和色调 于是
we've basically got brightness, the intensity of a color,
我们基本有了亮度 色彩的强度
how saturated it is, how brilliant the color is, and
色彩有多饱和 色彩有多明亮，
then which color you actually pick in the color wheel.
以及你在色轮上取的是什么颜色
So these are all representing, and these are consistent with the previous study,
这些和早前的研究是一致的
representing quantitative values that you may want to display geometrically or
它们一起表示数量数据 可用于几何
spatially.
或空间展示
We can also display other values.
我们还可以展示一些别的数值
For example, ordinal values, values, again,
例如 定序值
that you'll want to map to a visual display.
你想要对它们做可视化的展示
In ordinal's case, instead of quantitative,
在非定量 而是定序的情况
we don't know how much greater one value is to another.
我们不知道一个值 比另一个到底大了多少
We just know that one value is bigger than another or greater than another value.
仅仅是知道它比另外一个大
For example, shirt sizes.
举个例子 T恤的尺寸
We know that medium shirt is larger than a small shirt.
我们知道中码T恤要比小码T恤大
We just don't know how much larger.
只是我们不知道大了多少
So for ordinal data, position still wins out,
所以 对于定序类数据 “位置”仍然有优势
so position is still at the top of the list for indicating ordinal data values.
所以“位置”仍然在描述定序类数据值的 维度列表的顶端
But then we have density, saturation, and hue second, third, and fourth in the list.
但是随后我们在列表的第二 第三 第四位 看到的是密度 饱和度和色调
So whereas the brightness of a color, or how intense the color is,
所以不论颜色的亮度 颜色的强度
or which color you pick, it's difficult to make actual quantitative comparisons.
或者你具体取了哪个颜色 都很难做切实的定量的比较
It is actually quite easy to make the comparison itself.
不过实际上比较也是容易的
You can tell when one object is brighter than another object,
你可以说出一个东西比另一个要明亮
you just don't know how much brighter it is.
你只是不知道到底明亮了多少
And then the remainder of these stays in the same order,
然后剩下的部分的顺序保持不变
it just falls further down on the list.
只是它们排在了列表的底部
So length, angle, slope, area, and volume are a little bit less effective at
所以长度 角度 斜率 面积和体积等
looking at relative orders of things that don't have quantitative values.
比起描述定量的数值， 在描述相对循序时则不是那么的有效
And this gap here is filled in with some geometric mappings that don't
对于在展示定量值时没有意义的几何映射 这些位置被留为空白
make sense for quantitative values, things like texture, connection, and containment.
例如纹理 连接 包含关系
And so we wouldn't think of one texture as being different, quantitatively,
我们不会认为 一种纹理质和另一种相比起来 有定量的不同
than another texture, but you can make value judgments between textures, and
但是你可以在纹理之间用数值做评价，
so this is more textured than this is.
这个比那个纹理更丰富
You can make connections between objects, and
你可以在物件之间增加连接
these two objects are connected and this one isn't, and
这两个物件是连接了的 这个则没有
that sets up an ordering that's not necessarily quantitative.
于是 这样就建立了一个未必是定量的顺序
And finally, containment, the fact that one object contains another object, and
最后 包含关系 一个物件包含另外一个物件
a third object is not contained by that object,
第三个物件怎没有被包含
is another ordinal organization that doesn't make sense for quantitative data.
这是另外对于定量数据毫无意义的一种定序组织结构
And finally, there's a third category of data we can look at, nominal.
最后 我们还可以研究一下第三种数据分类 定类数据
These are categories of data.
这些是数据的类别
Ordinals are values that we can compare, but
定序值是我们能比较 但是
that we don't know how much greater one is to another.
不能知道一个具体比另一个大了多少的类别
With nominal values, these are categories that aren't comparable,
而定类值 是一类不能互相比较的分类
things like comparing a square to a circle.
就像不能把正方形和圆相比
A square isn't greater than a circle or less than a circle.
一个正方形不能比一个圆更大或者更小
They're just different.
他们是不同的
And so, again, position is still
这样一来 再一次 “位置” 仍然
the strongest indicator of difference for nominal data values,
是定类数据最强的差异标志维度
but then what would ordinarily be second?
但是随后谁又是第二个呢？
Density, saturation, hue, texture, connection, and
密度 饱和度 色调 材质 连接和
containment remains as powerful for nominal axes, except that hue and
包含关系 对于定类的数据仍然很有用 除了色调和
texture become stronger, and the rest of these become a little bit weaker.
纹理变得更加强烈 其余的都会稍微变得弱些
And so hue, the actual color in a color wheel, is a good indicator of category,
色调 在色轮中的真实颜色 是一个好的分类指标
even though it's a very poor indicator of actual quantities.
尽管对于数量型的数据来说 它是个较差的指标
And then, finally, length, angle, slope, volume, and
最后 长度 角度 斜率 体积和
area end up being similarly poor for
面积用来描述类别的时候
describing categories as they are for describing base sizes.
和描述基本尺寸一样效果较差
There's an additional value here that you can map categories to shape, so you can
这里还有一个额外的值 就是你可以将分类映射到形状
map nominal data to shape, and I've been using shape as an example of nominal data,
你就能将定类数据映射到“形状” 我也曾用“形状”当过一个定类数据的例子
circle, square, and so on, and that's more effective than mapping categories to,
圆 方形等等 比将分类映射到
for example, the length or angle of geometry.
长度 几何角度则要更为有效
So we've learned that there's many different ways of connecting our
所以我们学到了 有很多种不同的方法可以
data to different graphics attributes when we display data graphically for
将我们的数据和不同的图形属性， 在做数据可视化的展示时相连接
data visualization, and we've learned that some of these ways are better perceived
同时我们也知道了 有一些方法会比另外一些更有效
than others depending on whether the data is nominal, ordered, or quantitative.
这取决于数据是定类的 定序的 还是定量的
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community